Guide to the Hugh Fowell Great Performances Collection ARS.0100
Archive of Recorded Sound
Hugh Fowell Great Performances Collection
1980s-1990s
ARS.0100
2 boxes: 25 videocassettes
Archive of Recorded Sound
Home-recorded videocassettes of television broadcasts of opera from the Great Performances series.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Hugh Fowell Great Performances Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Rosemary Fowell in 1999.
Scope and Contents
Twenty-five VHS videocassettes of opera taped from the Great Performances television series, primarily of the Metropolitan Opera and largely of works by Mozart, Verdi, and Wagner. All were recorded off-air by Hugh Fowell.
Indexing Terms
Fowell, Hugh; Great performances (WNET (Television station: New York, N.Y.)).; Operas; Television programs.
- Nixon and China (Adams) - Houston Grand Opera, 1988; 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Mefistofele (Boito) - San Francisco Opera, with Ramey,Banackova, O'Neill, 1 videocassettes (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (Giordano) - Royal Opera, with Placido Domingo, Anna Tomowa Sintou, Georgio Zancanaro, 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- L'Africaine (Meyerbeer) - SF Opera, with Domingo, Verrett, Swenson, Diaz, 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutti (Mozart), 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Don Giovanni (Mozart) - Vienna State Opera, 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- The Magic Flute (Mozart), 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Marriage of Figaro (Mozart), 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Girl of the Golden West (Puccini) with Placido Domingo, Barbara Deniels, Sherril Milnes, 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Tosca (Puccini) with Domingo, Malfitano, Raimundi, Zubin Mehta, 1992; 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Rossini Birthday Gala, with June Anderson, Marilyn Horne, Frederick von Stade, 1992; 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Arabella (R. Strauss), 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Capriccio (R. Strauss) - Salzburg Festival, 1992; 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Die Fledermaus (J. Strauss) - Royal Opera London, 1 videocassette (Box 1)
- Falstaff (Verdi) with Paul Plishka, Marilyn Horne, Mirella Freni, Frank Lopardo, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- The Masked Ball (Verdi) - Philadelphia Opera Company, with Pavarotti, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Otello (Verdi) - Metropolitan Opera, with Domingo, Morris, Flemming, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Stifellio (Verdi) - Metropolitan Opera, with Domingo, Sharon Sweat; Turandot (Puccini) - San Francisco Opera, with Eva Marton, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- La Traviata (Verdi) - New York City Opera, with Janice Hall, Stephen Mark Brown, Louis Otey, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Gotterdammerung (Wagner) - Metropolitan Opera, with James Morris, Siegfried Jerusalem, Hildegaard Behrens, Christie Ludwig, Matti Salminen, Anthony Laffell, etc., 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Das Reingold (Wagner) - Metropolitan Opera, with James Morris, Sirfried Jerusalem, Christa Ludwig, Kari-Anne Haggander, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Siegfried (Wagner) - Metropolitan Opera, with Siegfried Jerusalem, Hildegaard Behrens, James Morris, Heiz Zednikl, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Die Walkure (Wagner) - Metropolitan Opera, with Behrens, Morris, Norman, Ludwig, Lakes, Moll, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Pygmalion, with Peter O'Toole, Margo Kidder; Metropolitan Opera Silver Anniversary Gala; 3rd Act Rigoletto, portions 3rd Act Otello, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Pavarotti Plus, with Juan Pons, Barbara Dever, Deborah Voight, Stephen Mark Brown, Elizabeth Holleque, Robert Candussi, April Milio, Eugenie Grunewald, 1 videocassette (Box 2)
- Three Tenors - Los Angeles Concert (Domingo, Carreras, Pavarotti), 1994-07-16; 1 videocassette (Box 2)